Guide to the Investigation Files of the Rapp-Coudert Committee TAM.533
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Microfilm Reel List (with Cross-Reference to Original Box and Folder Locations), 1919-1953
  - City College: Anti-Fascist Association (Copies of "The Bulletin of the Anti-Fascist Association"), 1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0416, Box-folder 2-RC80)
  - City College: House Plan (Student Organization) Flyers, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0444, Box-folder 2-RC81)
  - City College: Uptown - Incudes Interviews with Various Faculty Members, Constitutions of Several Young Communist League Clubs, and Other Student Organization Materials, 1942-1945 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0448, Box-folder 2-RC82)
  - City College: Student Publications (e.g. "Collegiate Digest", "Main Events", "The Reporter) Many Include Articles Concerning the Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0488, Box-folder 2-RC83)
  - Committee Resolutions and Official Statements, 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0608, Box-folder 2-RC84)
  - City College: Student Organizations: Includes Interviews, Pamphlets, Speaker Lists, Calendars, Flyers, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0651, Box-folder 2-RC85)
  - Communism: Pamphlets, Articles, Flyers, 1933-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 4-0780, Box-folder 2-RC86)
  - Communism: Force and Violence - Articles and Excerpts of Articles from Various Publications (e.g.The Teachers International, The Communist, Party Organizer); Pamphlets, Membership Lists, 1920-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 5-0001, Box-folder 2-RC87)
  - Communism: Imperialist War (excerpts from The Communist International, The Daily Worker, The Communist), 1940-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 5-0292, Box-folder 2-RC88)
  - Communism: Party Discipline (articles and article excerpts), 1924-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 5-0312, Box-folder 2-RC89)
  - Communist Party: Includes Journal and Newspaper Articles, CP Publicity Materials, 1935-1941, uundated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 5-0384, Box-folder 2-RC90)
  - Communist Party: Brooklyn College: Includes Copies of The Staff Issued by Brooklyn College Unit of the Communist Party, Correspondence, Several Browder Speeches and Other CP materials, 1935-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 5-0518, Box-folder 2-RC91)
  - Communist Party: City College (Primarily copies of Teacher Worker), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 6-0001, Box-folder 3-RC92,1)
  - Communist Party: City College (Primarily copies of Teacher Worker, some duplicates from previous folder), 1935-1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 6-0236, Box-folder 3-RC92,2)
  - Communism: Reports of Interviews, Phone Calls, Meetings and Related Materials (Includes Such Interviewees as A. Philip Randolph, Whittaker Chambers and Sidney Hook); Trip Memorandum (Nov 11-13, 1940) Describes Sharing of Information with Dies Committee and US Dept. of State., 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 6-0522, Box-folder 3-RC93)
  - Communism: Reports of Interviews, Phone Calls, Meetings and Related Materials (significant focus on Teachers Union of the City of New York in this and previous folder), 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 6-0818, Box-folder 3-RC94)
  - Communism: Reports of Interviews (including Sidney Hook), Phone Calls, Meetings and Related Materials; Includes Lists of Suspected Individuals, Organizations and Publications; Items Relating to the National Federation for Constitutional Liberties, 1937-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0001, Box-folder 3-RC95)
  - Documents on Subversive Activities Submitted to Rapp- Coudert Labeled as "Unimportant" by Committee: Includes Copies of Various Publications such as Harlem Lesson Plan, Bulletin, Friends of the Public Schools, Guild Teacher and Newsletter of the Brooklyn College Teachers Union, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0314, Box-folder 3-RC96)
  - Material from A.B. Owens Detective Agency: Focused on the Teacher Worker Published at CCNY (Involves Isidor Begun; also Horton, Howard, Ackley, Stone and Small), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0440, Box-folder 3-RC97)
  - Communist Party: Candidates, Financial Statements (Includes Reports of Contributions/Receipts and Expenditures by the NY Communist Party), 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0451, Box-folder 3-RC98)
  - David, Henry (Instructor, Queens College): Card with Brief Information, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0598, Box-folder 3-RC99)
  - Davidson, Benjamin (Teacher, New York City Public Schools): School Records, Applications for License, Correspondence and other Related Materials; also Transcript of 6/8/1934 Mass Meeting (sponsored by the Teachers Union of the CIty of New York) on the Topic of Academic Freedom (initial speaker was Norman Thomas), 1924-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 7-0601, Box-folder 3-RC100)
  - Davidson, Benjamin: Daily Worker (photostats), 1920s (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0001, Box-folder 3-RC101)
  - Davidson, David (Assistant Professor, Chemistry Department, CCNY), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0044, Box-folder 3-RC102)
  - Davidson, Eve, nee Chambers (Teacher, PS 101, Manhattan): Official Documents including Teaching License Applications, Medical Exam, School Transcripts, and Name Change, 1924-1926 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0047, Box-folder 3-RC103)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1938 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0077, Box-folder 3-RC104)
  - Devereaux, William, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0081, Box-folder 3-RC105)
  - DeSola, Ralph: Informant Testimony (re: Isidore Begun, Elizabeth DeWarde, Yetta Feigenbaum and Morris Schappes), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0084, Box-folder 3-RC106)
  - DeWarde, Elizabeth: Testimony of Informant, List of Documentation, History of Teaching Experience (Primarily at PS 47, Brooklyn), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0091, Box-folder 3-RC107)
  - DeWitt Clinton High School, Bronx: Testimony, Interviews, Correspondence, Reports, Flyers, Class Syllabi and Reading Lists (Providing information on individuals and organizations), 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0099, Box-folder 3-RC108)
  - Diamond, Max (DeWitt Clinton High School; member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun), 1937, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0219, Box-folder 3-RC109)
  - Dies Committee (includes Doctor Matthews' Amazing Statement Before the Dies' Committee Investigating Un-American Activities, a 30-page document highlighting Communist-leaning organizations, and Interlocking Chart Showing Radical Connections of Certain Organizations, prepared by Allied Patriotic Societies, Inc.), 1937-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0223, Box-folder 3-RC110)
  - Diffie, Bailey W. (CCNY): Includes Correspondence with the Council for Pan American Democracy and Letters Concerning his Resignation from the Teachers Union, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0254, Box-folder 3-RC111)
  - Dodd, Bella (Legislative Representative of the Teachers Union of the City of New York): Legal Document Regarding Contempt Charges against Charles J. Hendley (President, Teachers Union) and Isidore Begun Flyer, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0268, Box-folder 3-RC112)
  - Doughty, Howard (English, CCNY): Interview, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0275, Box-folder 3-RC113)
  - Dubrowsky, David: Includes Item from Joint Information Bureau in Moscow and Correspondence Regarding Book Exchanges (much of the material in this folder is in Russian), 1925, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0278, Box-folder 3-RC114)
  - Dunn, Robert: Testimony Naming Dunn as Communist. Flyers, Information Summary, Dunn Article Is This Slavery?, Waiver of Immunity, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0294, Box-folder 3-RC115)
  - High Schools, Eastern District: Includes Testimony of Joseph Greenberg, Teacher; also Reports, Flyers, Testimony of Others, Interview Notes, Correspondence, and Many Information Cards on Various Individuals at Different Schools, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0337, Box-folder 3-RC116)
  - Edel, Abraham (Assistant Professor, Philosophy), 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0504, Box-folder 3-RC117)
  - Edel, May (Brooklyn College, Anthropology), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0513, Box-folder 3-RC118)
  - Educational Workers International: Portions of The Teachers Journal (photostats), 1928-1932 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0516, Box-folder 3-RC119)
  - Eisenberger, Sidney (Chemistry, CCNY), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0545, Box-folder 3-RC120)
  - Emergency Peace Mobilization: Includes Report of November 11th Rally at Mecca Temple, 55th Street, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0555, Box-folder 3-RC121)
  - Equality (publication): Includes Reports of Several Investigations for the Committee, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0569, Box-folder 3-RC122)
  - High Schools: Erasmus Hall, Brooklyn: Includes Hearing Testimony (Witness Peter J. McKenzie, NYFD), Information Summary re: John P. MCNeill (Erasmus Hall Principal), Flyers, Articles and Other Materials, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0576, Box-folder 3-RC123)
  - High Schools: Evander Childs, Bronx - Information Summary, Correspondence and Other Material Regarding Hyman Alpern (Erasmus Childs Principal); Letter from Mrs. Erasmus Childs; Articles, Brochures and Other Related Items, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0624, Box-folder 3-RC124)
  - Evansohn, Jacob, [1936] (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0726, Box-folder 3-RC125)
  - Ewen, Frederic (Brooklyn College): Article, Information Sheet and Photograph, 1938-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0737, Box-folder 3-RC126)
  - Federation of Youth Organization: Coney Island and Brighton Beach - Includes Investigative Report, Constitution and List of Member Groups, 1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0749, Box-folder 3-RC127)
  - Fenlon, Edward I. (Brooklyn College, testified before Dies Committee): Includes Interviews at His Home, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0761, Box-folder 3-RC128)
  - Feigenbaum, Yetta (Candidate for Delegate to AFT Convention): Includes Information Summary, Correspondence and Photograph, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0772, Box-folder 3-RC129)
  - Feuer, Lewis S. (Philosophy), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0788, Box-folder 3-RC130)
  - Fink, Ruth (Hunter College), 1935 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0791, Box-folder 3-RC131)
  - Finkel, William (CCNY), 1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0796, Box-folder 3-RC132)
  - Finkelstein, Moses (CCNY, History): Includes Statement of Educational Principles by Eleven Teachers of Social Science at CCNY; Syllabus of Ancient History Class; 1940 Review of Finkelstein's Teaching and Other Related Materials, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0807, Box-folder 3-RC133)
  - Fuller, Thomas G. (Former Substitute Teacher, Sheet Metal; Fought in Spain 1937-1938): Correspondence Including Recommendation to Revoke Substitute Teaching License for False Statements, 1939-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0888, Box-folder 3-RC134)
  - Foner, Morris "Moe" (Clerk, Registrar's Office, CCNY), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0898, Box-folder 4-RC135)
  - Foner, Henry: Includes Information Summary and Photograph, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 8-0911, Box-folder 4-RC136)
  - Foner, Jack D.(History, CCNY): Includes Charges and Responses; Transcript of Testimony at Public Hearing before the Committee; Letters Supporting and Denouncing Foner, along with Other Correspondence; Statement of Resignation from City College; Course Materials, Photograph, Many Articles and Information Cards, 1935-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-001, Box-folder 4-RC137)
  - Foner, Philip S.(History, CCNY): Includes Majority Report of Trial Committee of Board of Higher Education; Correspondence, Articles, Photograph and Course Information, 1935-1944, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0129, Box-folder 4-RC138)
  - Garland Fund: Includes Photocopy of American Fund for Public Service Report, 1925-1928, 1929 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0219, Box-folder 4-RC139)
  - Gastwirth, Paul (ALP member expelled by Queens County Executive Committee), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0269, Box-folder 4-RC140)
  - Geiger, Theodore (CCNY, Columbia-History): Includes Hearing Testimony, 1941-1943, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0272, Box-folder 4-RC141)
  - German-American League for Culture, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0315, Box-folder 4-RC142)
  - German-American Writers Association: Interview with William Gaede (Asst. Professor of German at Brooklyn College), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0321, Box-folder 4-RC143)
  - Gideonse, Harry (President, Brooklyn College): New York Post Profile, Summary of Interviews and Report on his Address to Brooklyn College Faculty, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0325, Box-folder 4-RC144)
  - Gipfel, Paul (Brooklyn College): Includes Letter to Gideonse Requesting Removal of Gipfel from Teaching Post at Brooklyn College, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0344, Box-folder 4-RC145)
  - Gold, Hyman E. (CCNY French Department): Includes Information Sheets, Correspondence, Letters of Support and Interview Summary of Informant Canning Regarding Gold, 1938-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0350, Box-folder 4-RC146)
  - Goldfield, Abraham (Typographer for Communist Party publications): Includes Trial Brief, Record of his Activities, Photographs, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0367, Box-folder 4-RC147)
  - Goldfield, Joseph (Employer of Charles Wohl and William Trachtenberg), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0431, Box-folder 4-RC148)
  - Goldway, David (CCNY/Townsend-Harris High School; Member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun): Includes Memorandum of the Principle Points of the Case, News Articles, Photographs and Teachers Union Membership Meeting Minutes, 1937-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0434, Box-folder 4-RC149)
  - Gordon, Alice (High School Student arrested for selling The Sunday Worker): Includes Memo to Committee, Interview and Description of Arrest, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0505, Box-folder 4-RC150)
  - Gottschall, Morton, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0528, Box-folder 4-RC151)
  - Grand Jury Presentations of Kings County Grand Jury and of the April 1942 Grand Jury (Extended), 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0531, Box-folder 4-RC152)
  - Grebanier, Bernard D.N. (Brooklyn College, English Department): Includes Grebanier Testimony, Private Discussions, Further Examinations, Many "Names" not Mentioned in Public Testimony, "Brooklyn College Suspects List", 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0568, Box-folder 4-RC153)
  - Griffin, John (Economics, formerly of Brooklyn College), 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0777, Box-folder 4-RC154)
  - Gross, Frank (Member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee to Elect Isidore Begun, Candidate for City Council 1937), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0802, Box-folder 4-RC155)
  - Group, Seymour: Includes Interview and Subpoena, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0806, Box-folder 4-RC156)
  - High Schools - Grover Cleveland (Queens): Letter of Dr. Charles Tonsor, Princial, to Mr.Frederick Ernst, Assistant Supreintendent of Schools, on Lack of Subversive Activity, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0809, Box-folder 4-RC157)
  - Gustafson, Elton T.: Includes Handwriting Analysis, 1939-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0815, Box-folder 4-RC158)
  - Halpern, Frieda (Teacher, Public School 156, Brooklyn), 1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 9-0842, Box-folder 4-RC159)
  - Harlem: Schools, Organizations (including CPUSA) - Various Articles, Memos, Notes, Correspondence,Interview Summaries, Pamphlets, Flyers (including "Harlem Lesson Plan", Gustav Schoenchen case, Proceedings of CPUSA Convention), 1936-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0001, Box-folder 4-RC160)
  - High School Digest: Duplicates(Carbon Copies) of Case Number RC167: Includes List of Schools/Principals, Memo on ASU, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0280, Box-folder 4-RC161)
  - Board of Higher Education Democratization By-Laws: Includes History of By-laws, Correspondence with Brooklyn College, Telegram to Board from Morris Schappes and Other Teachers, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0383, Box-folder 4-RC162)
  - Hintz, Howard (Assistant Professor, English, Brooklyn College): Memo of Interview, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0513, Box-folder 4-RC163)
  - Horowitz, Leon J., undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0517, Box-folder 4-RC164)
  - Hecht, Nathan, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0527, Box-folder 4-RC165)
  - High Schools: Memos - Includes Minutes of Teachers Union Delegate Assembly, Lists of High School Teachers and Principals, 1936-1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0530, Box-folder 4-RC166)
  - High Schools Principals Digests (of Subversive Activities/Organizations): Includes Summary of Principals' and Teachers' Statement (see Case Number RC-161), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0545, Box-folder 4-RC167)
  - High Schools: Haaren High School (10th Avenue and 19th Street, Manhattan) - Interview Summaries, ASU Flyer, Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0618, Box-folder 4-RC168)
  - Hoch, Myron L. (CCNY Economics, Active in Teachers Union), 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0675, Box-folder 4-RC169)
  - Hollander, Bernard, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0717, Box-folder 4-RC170)
  - Hunter College, Items 1-6, 1933-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 10-0721, Box-folder 4-RC171,1)
  - Hunter College, Items 7-15, 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0001, Box-folder 4-RC171,2)
  - Hunter College, Items 16-End, 1940-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0201, Box-folder 4-RC171,3)
  - Horowitz, Philip (Seward Park High School, Member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun, Candidate for City Council 1937), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0319, Box-folder 4-RC172)
  - Hertzman, Max: Photograph, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0323, Box-folder 4-RC173)
  - Hurlinger, Ivan (CCNY, School of Business), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0330, Box-folder 4-RC174)
  - Hutt, Max L. (CCNY, Sociology), 1940, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0343, Box-folder 4-RC175)
  - Principals' Letters Regarding Radical Acts of Students and Teachers: Includes Interview Summaries and Flyers, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0360, Box-folder 4-RC176)
  - Board of Higher Education: Includes John T. Flynn, Lawton McCall, Joseph Schlossburg, Charles Tuttle, Eugene Colligan (Hunter College), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 11-0466, Box-folder 4-RC177)
  - In Fact Newsletter, 1940-1942 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0001, Box-folder 5-RC178)
  - Irvin, Oscar William (Brooklyn College Director of Summer Session and Professor of Math): Interview Summary, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0236, Box-folder 5-RC179)
  - Instructional Staff Association (CCNY), 1935, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0240, Box-folder 5-RC180)
  - Certificate of Incorporation - International Publishers and Booksellers, Inc. (Photocopies), 1924 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0251, Box-folder 5-RC181)
  - International Labor Defense (Photocopy of Labor Defender), 1936 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0269, Box-folder 5-RC182)
  - International Workers Order, 1933-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0272, Box-folder 5-RC183)
  - Johnson, Oakley (Faculty Advisor CCNY Liberal Club), 1933 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0296, Box-folder 5-RC184)
  - James Monroe High School: Includes 1934 yearbook, Correspondence, Memoranda, Flyers, Booklet Roosevelt Heads for War by William Z. Foster, 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0300, Box-folder 5-RC185)
  - James Monroe High School (Brooklyn), 1935, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0546, Box-folder 5-RC186)
  - Julia Richmond High School (Manhattan), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0568, Box-folder 5-RC187)
  - John Adams High School (Queens, New York), 1940-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0572, Box-folder 5-RC188)
  - Johnson, Edgar, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0582, Box-folder 5-RC189)
  - Kaiser, Samuel (photograph), undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0585, Box-folder 5-RC190)
  - Karr, Benjamin (formerly CCNY; Central Commercial High School shorthand and typing teacher): Testimony and Correspondence, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0593, Box-folder 5-RC191)
  - Kirshner, Harold (German, Public School System), 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0609, Box-folder 5-RC192)
  - Klein, Henry (Brooklyn College, History; then, PS 163, Brooklyn), 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0617, Box-folder 5-RC193)
  - Kloss, Martin (CCNY Student), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0646, Box-folder 5-RC194)
  - Koppelman, Hyman (member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun, City Council Candidate 1937), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0652, Box-folder 5-RC195)
  - Kraus, A.J. (formerly CCNY - Philosophy), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0656, Box-folder 5-RC196)
  - Krumbein, Charles (State Treasurer of Communist Party), 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0665, Box-folder 5-RC197)
  - Kulansky, Harry: Interview Summary, Daniel Bell re: Kulansky, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0672, Box-folder 5-RC198)
  - Lederman, Abraham (Public School 64, Manhattan, member of Teachers Non-Partisan Committee for the Election of Isidore Begun), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0676, Box-folder 5-RC199)
  - Lederman, Nelle R. (CCNY Psychologist in Clinic and Teacher in Graduate Division): Includes Transcript of Private Hearing, Correspondence, Informant Statements, 1935-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0680, Box-folder 5-RC200)
  - Leikind, Seymour S. (Chemistry Department, Brooklyn), 1941-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0741, Box-folder 5-RC201)
  - Lehrman, Alexander, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0805, Box-folder 5-RC202)
  - Landau, Victor (Fellow in Music) (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0817, Box-folder 5-RC203)
  - Lipschitz, Moe (in charge of children's organization work for CP in NYC), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0820, Box-folder 5-RC204)
  - Lash, Joe (Joseph P. Lash, National Secretary of ASU, 1939) (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0823, Box-folder 5-RC205)
  - Lightbody, Charles W. (St. Lawrence University History Professor), 1942-1943 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0830, Box-folder 5-RC206)
  - LeDoux, Norman (Former CCNY student, part-time clerk in Evening Session while student), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0843, Box-folder 5-RC207)
  - Lee, Albert (Freshman CCNY, former member ASU at Townsend Harris High School): Interview Summary, 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 12-0857, Box-folder 5-RC208)
  - Lerman, Louis (CCNY, Clerical Fellow): Includes New Masses (Aug 1935 and Nov 1936), Scope (1934), Blast (May-June 1934) and Space (Oct 1934); Lerman Alleged Activities and Correspondence, 1934-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0001, Box-folder 5-RC209)
  - Lynn, Myron (former CCNY student), 1940 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0121, Box-folder 5-RC210)
  - Lieberman, Elias (Principal, Thomas Jefferson High School, 1924-1940), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0125, Box-folder 5-RC211)
  - Lehrman, Alexander, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0130, Box-folder 5-RC212)
  - Lafayette High School - Brooklyn: Includes ASU and Teachers' Union Materials; Publications such as Teachers News; Interview Summaries; Correspondence, 1939-1941, undated (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0134, Box-folder 5-RC213)
  - Levitch, William: Private Hearing Exhibit (Workers School Course Announcement), 1939 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0351, Box-folder 5-RC214)
  - Lieblein Exhibit: Private Hearing Inclulding Der Amerika-Deutsche, 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0357, Box-folder 5-RC215)
  - McGill, Vivian J. (Hunter College), 1936-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0367, Box-folder 5-RC216)
  - McGill Exhibits - Private Hearings: Photostats of Selections from New Masses and The Communist, 1938-1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0407, Box-folder 5-RC217)
  - McLoughlin, William (CCNY, student president of the evening classes), 1941 (Reel R-7860, Reel frame 13-0430, Box-folder 5-RC218)